Ben Platt

Belfast, UK - BT38 7NW - plattben22@icloud.com - 07748940301 - github.com/BenPlatt-01

Highly motivated and determined Computer Science graduate with a strong academic background and a passion for technology and software engineering with a specific interest in game design and application development. With 7 years of retail/retail management experience and a year of industry experience I have developed excellent teamworking and networking skills as well as maintaining a strong work ethic. Looking to apply my technical and soft skills within a working environment.

Personal Details

Driving License: Held for 7+ years

Eligible to work in UK: Yes

Highest Level of Education: Level 6 – BSc Computer Science

Industries: Retail, Software Development, Al Development, Research Engineer, Retail

Management

Overall years of experience: 7

Work Experience

Junior Research Engineer

ECIT, Queen's University - Belfast

Sept 2022 - Sept 2023

Keyholder

Spar – Carrickfergus

Sept 2023 - Present

ECIT – In-Depth:

- Worked in an agile working environment with weekly/bi-weekly sprint planning meetings with scrum master.
- Worked on a variety of different projects from start to finish so was able to see the full development lifecycle. Projects also were a mixture of solo and team-based projects.
- First project was automated testing of a questionnaire system that was hosted on Azure and used schemas to generate an answer sheet at the end. I was involved in testing the schemas against our test suites we had developed.
- Second project was a team-based project based on Honeypot Data Analysis. This was
 the other placement students and I's biggest project we had during our placement year.
 The issue was there was 25+ honeypots with a lot of data on them but they were in all
 different formats and styles. So, we decided to bring them all to one comparable format
 (JSON).
- Developed the second project in Linux to pull down the Honeypot data each day and use schemas to produce a legible version that would then be stored and dated for future use.
- Final project was an Al Model demonstration of how you can bypass facial recognition. This was built on a Raspberry Pi and was packaged using a Flask API.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python, Java, C++, C#, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Bash, PowerShell

Frameworks: React Native, Flask

Tools & Platforms: Azure, AWS, GIT, Postman, Ubuntu, Raspberry PI, Unity, GameMaker Studio,

Piskel

Databases: Firebase, MongoDB

Projects (Technical Skills)

- Final Year Project I developed an application built within React Native to help people living with dementia whenever they have an episode of confusion or forgetfulness. The first iteration of the application was predeveloped by a previous final year student, but it was within an older framework and wouldn't run properly. I was responsible for doing a lot of refactoring and fixing of a pre-existing codebase as well as linking the application to a backend so I could start to implement features I wanted to add to the application. I decided to use Firebase as the main database within the application. Once I had this implemented, I was able to create and store log in details as well as link a caregiver's account to a patients account. This allowed a 'caregiver account' to update details and emergency contact info of the 'patient account'. There was also a facial recognition script that was being implemented as a log in feature. The application was packaged using Expo and finally put onto a tablet that was used for demonstration purposes.
- Personal Game Design Project As someone who has a massive passion for the gaming industry as well as coding and creating, I decided to take on a personal project of creating my own 2D game. Through this I was able to learn and improve with different technologies and software. I started using Game Maker Studio to make the shell of the game but soon realised it didn't have the features I was looking for so moved to Unity to develop the rest of the game. The sprites I needed to create were made using Piskel and Aesprite, I adopted an 8-bit look for the game as it made it easier to create sprites.
- Education Projects I have over 7 years of IT Experience through my educational background. This includes things ranging from reports and presentations to fully tested and working applications. Through this experience I have gained fantastic problemsolving skills and time management skills in order to meet deadlines.

Education

- Queen's University BSc Computer Science
 - 0 2020-2024
- Northern Regional College Level 3 Extended Diploma in IT
 - 0 2018-2020
 - Triple Distinction Star
- Carrickfergus Grammar School GCSEs
 - 0 2016-2018
 - 8 GCSEs Grade A*-C including Maths, IT and English.